<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on un01s notes</title>
    <link>https://un01s.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on un01s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 18:00:21 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://un01s.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rust on ESP32</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220111/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 18:00:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220111/</guid>
      <description>Start to look at the toolchain for Rust on ESP32 family modules. After some googling, here is the first result.
Clearly the toolchain is working in its early stage. $ cargo build is OK. But esptool does not work. This requires further investigation. Instead the flashing tool from esp-idf is used directly to flash one esp32 dev board.
References:
 Rust on ESP32 rust esp32 std demo  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SigmundFreud: mass delusion</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220108/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 18:09:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220108/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Of special importance is the case in which substantial numbers of people, acting in concert, try to assure themselves of happiness and protection against suffering through a delusional reshaping of reality. The religions of mankind too must be described as example of mass delusion. Of course, no one who still shares a delusion will ever recognize it as such.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;We never have so little protection against suffering as when we are in love; we are never so desolate when we have lost the object of our love or its love for us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joan Didion: Why I Write</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20211224/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 11:01:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20211224/</guid>
      <description>Had my credentials been in order I would never have become a writer. Had I been blessed with even limited access to my own mind there would have been no reason to write. I write entirely to find out what I’m thinking, what I’m looking at, what I see and what it means. What I want and what I fear. Why did the oil refineries around Carquinez Strait seem sinister to me in the summer of 1956?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joan Didion</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20211223/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 14:43:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20211223/</guid>
      <description>It all comes back. Perhaps it is difficult to see the value in having one’s self back in that kind of mood, but I do see it; I think we are well advised to keep on nodding terms with the people we used to be whether we find them attractive company or not. Otherwise they turn up unannounced and surprise us, come hammering on the mind’s door at 4 a.m. of a bad night and demand to know who deserted them, who betrayed them, who is going to make amends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emily Dickinson</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20211212/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 13:04:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20211212/</guid>
      <description>In this short Life that only lasts an hour
How much - how little - is within our power</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
