<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on un01s notes</title>
    <link>https://un01s.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on un01s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 16:18:57 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://un01s.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reading Code of Toit [FE25]</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220225/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 16:18:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220225/</guid>
      <description>When I started to port the code to ESP32S3 following the example of ESP32C3, I realized I had to read the code closely. Here are the notes along the way.
where does the code get started on esp32? Based on esp-idf, Toit creates a new environment with a lot of free goodies such as over-the-air update through WiFi, easy tasks, and a high-level programming language with a built-in virtual machine for developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Paul Farmer</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220221/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 20:53:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220221/</guid>
      <description>Today Putin ordered troops into pro-Russian region of eastern Ukraine in the name of peacekeeping. Ukraine invaded.
Then I saw the news of Dr. Paul Farmer. &amp;ldquo;The idea that some lives matter less is the root of all that is wrong with the world.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Infinite Dead</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220205/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 19:27:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220205/</guid>
      <description>I remember once offering to an editor an article which began with a reference to the experience of last century. &amp;ldquo;Oh,&amp;rdquo; he said, &amp;ldquo;leave out the history and come to the present.&amp;rdquo; I felt like going to him over a thousand miles and taking him by the lapels and saying, &amp;ldquo;Dear, dear jackass! Don&amp;rsquo;t you understand that the past is the present; that without what was, nothing is? That, of the infinite dead, the living are but unimportant bits?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do not ask your children to strive</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220204/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 18:58:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220204/</guid>
      <description>Do not ask your children
to strive for extraordinary lives.
Such striving may seem admirable,
but it is the way of foolishness.
Help them instead to find the wonder
and the marvel of an ordinary life.
Show them the joy of tasting
tomatoes, apples and pears.
Show them how to cry
when pets and people die.
Show them the infinite pleasure
in the touch of a hand.
And make the ordinary come alive for them</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading experience</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220129/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 13:45:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220129/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;People without hope not only don’t write novels, but what is more to the point, they don’t read them. They don’t take long looks at anything, because they lack the courage. The way to despair is to refuse to have any kind of experience, and the novel, of course, is a way to have experience. The lady who only read books that improved her mind was taking a safe course - and a hopeless one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isolated but still connected</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220126/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 11:45:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220126/</guid>
      <description>The internet introduces the digital dimension of our society. Then this pandemic makes isolation often. Only the internet makes it bearable. Yes, we may be isolated from each other but we are still connected in many ways. For example, art is one way to share our common experience in words, melody, shapes and colors. But I am not sure about either NFT or WEB3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mindfulness, Understanding, and Calmness</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220125/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 21:16:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220125/</guid>
      <description>The good and the bad are everywhere all the time. While reading stories and watching movies there are always heroes and villains in these endless dramas. There are always Don Quixote and Sancho. What am I? What are you? A mixture of good and bad. That&amp;rsquo;s all. What if we stop dividing us into black and white?
  One teaching of Budha is now and here. What does it mean?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Jaguar to update toit code over WiFi</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220117/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 12:12:11 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220117/</guid>
      <description>The Jaguar tool is great.
Use an Airport to setup a WiFi network. Then download the binary of Jaguar. Run the following commands one after another. The second command requires the WiFi credentials. Use CTRL+C to stop the third one. To run the forth and the fifth command, put your computer on the same WiFi network as the esp32 device.
$./jag setup $./jag flash $./jag monitor $./jag scan $./jag run hello.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wasm3 on ESP32</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220116/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 15:40:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220116/</guid>
      <description>Stumbled on this repo.
Run the modified code on one snowflake with 25 RGB LEDs (ws2812b-2020).
Check the video on my twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toit on M5stack Core2</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220115/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 21:02:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220115/</guid>
      <description>Build some examples in toit and flash it to M5Core2.
There is no problem to follow the steps in one toit discussion. While trying the step4 for ft63xx. Found a typo in package.yaml. mpu6886 should be ft63xx.
Another issue is that the touch seems not working after unplugging the USB cable. Will investigate further. Will try jaguar tool later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust on ESP32</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220111/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 18:00:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220111/</guid>
      <description>Start to look at the toolchain for Rust on ESP32 family modules. After some googling, here is the first result.
Clearly the toolchain is working in its early stage. $ cargo build OK. But esptool does not work. This requires further investigation. Instead the flashing tool from esp-idf is used directly to flash one esp32 dev board.
Update 2022.01.14: Both espflash and espmonitor are working.
References:
 Rust on ESP32 rust esp32 std demo  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SigmundFreud: mass delusion</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220108/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 18:09:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20220108/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Of special importance is the case in which substantial numbers of people, acting in concert, try to assure themselves of happiness and protection against suffering through a delusional reshaping of reality. The religions of mankind too must be described as example of mass delusion. Of course, no one who still shares a delusion will ever recognize it as such.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;We never have so little protection against suffering as when we are in love; we are never so desolate when we have lost the object of our love or its love for us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joan Didion: Why I Write</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20211224/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 11:01:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20211224/</guid>
      <description>Had my credentials been in order I would never have become a writer. Had I been blessed with even limited access to my own mind there would have been no reason to write. I write entirely to find out what I’m thinking, what I’m looking at, what I see and what it means. What I want and what I fear. Why did the oil refineries around Carquinez Strait seem sinister to me in the summer of 1956?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joan Didion</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20211223/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 14:43:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20211223/</guid>
      <description>It all comes back. Perhaps it is difficult to see the value in having one’s self back in that kind of mood, but I do see it; I think we are well advised to keep on nodding terms with the people we used to be whether we find them attractive company or not. Otherwise they turn up unannounced and surprise us, come hammering on the mind’s door at 4 a.m. of a bad night and demand to know who deserted them, who betrayed them, who is going to make amends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emily Dickinson</title>
      <link>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20211212/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 13:04:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://un01s.github.io/posts/20211212/</guid>
      <description>In this short Life that only lasts an hour
How much - how little - is within our power</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
